// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The first emission line of hydrogen atomic spectom in balmer series appears at(R:Rydberg constant)?",
    answer: "5R/36cm⁻¹",
    options: [
      "5R/36cm⁻¹",
      "3R/4cm⁻¹",
      "R/144cm⁻¹",
      "9R/400cm⁻¹"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The ion that is ISO electronic with Co is?",
    answer: "NO⁺",
    options: [
      "NO⁺",
      "O₂⁺",
      "O₂⁻",
      "N₂⁺"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "10ml if 0.05m H₄SO₄ is diluted to 100ml with what is the Pᴴ of the resultant solution?",
    answer: "2.0",
    options: [
      "2.0",
      "1.0",
      "2.3",
      "12.7"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Calculate the volume of water to be added to 200ml of 0.02N NaoH solutionⁿ to get 0.01N NaoH solutionⁿ?",
    answer: "200ml",
    options: [
      "200ml",
      "300ml",
      "400ml",
      "250ml"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Calculate the weight of Na₂Co₃ present in 500ml of 0.1m solution of sodium carbonate?",
    answer: "5.3g",
    options: [
      "5.0m",
      "5.5g",
      "5.3g",
      "5.1g"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Number of covalent bonds in water molecule is?",
    answer: "Two",
    options: [
      "One",
      "Three",
      "Four",
      "Two"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 7,
    question: "When 9.65 colombs of electricity is passed through a solutionⁿ of AgNo₃(at wt of Ag=107.87g taking as 108.0)the amount of silver deposited is?",
    answer: "10.8gm",
    options: [
      "10.8gm",
      "5.4gm",
      "16.2gm",
      "21.2gm"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The EMF of a glounic cell consisting of 2n⁺²/2n(0.76v)and fe²⁺/fe(044v)?",
    answer: "+0.32v",
    options: [
      "+1.20v",
      "-1.20v",
      "0.32v",
      "+0.32v"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Electrolysis of an aqueous solution of sodium acetate gas?",
    answer: "Ethane",
    options: [
      "Ethane",
      "Ethylene",
      "Actylene",
      "Methane"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Metal at the top of electronegative serial is?",
    answer: "Most active",
    options: [
      "Most stable",
      "Least active",
      "Most noble",
      "Most active"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Free radical polymeration can be initiated by using?",
    answer: "dibenzoyl peroxide",
    options: [
      "venzoic acid",
      "dibenzoyl peroxide",
      "nitro ethane",
      "benzolphenone"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The monomers used in the manufacture of Nylon:6,10 are?",
    answer: "Adipic acid and butadiene",
    options: [
      "Sebasis acid and hexamethylene diamine",
      "Adipic acid and butadiene",
      "Sebasis acid and butadiene",
      "Adipic acid and hexamethylene diamine"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Oil usually pushes out itself due to?",
    answer: "hydraustic pressure of natural gas",
    options: [
      "hydraustic pressure of natural gas",
      "Compressed air",
      "Harmful sulphur compounds",
      "Neptha(or)solvent spirit"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Pathigenic bacteria present in water is removed by?",
    answer: "Chlorination",
    options: [
      "Lime-soda process",
      "Zedite process",
      "Ion exchange process",
      "Chlorination"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which of the following ia used in estimation of chemict oxygen demand(COD)?",
    answer: "K₂Cr₂O₇+50%H₂So₄",
    options: [
      "Methyl orange",
      "K₂Cr₂O₇+50%H₂So₄",
      "CaCl₂+50%H₂So₄",
      "Alum+Cao"
    ]
  }, 
];